Anandukrishnan Narayanan

Senior Software Developer

Professional Software Engineer with 5 years and 2 months of experience in developing robust code for high-volume businesses using both JEE stack and open source technology stack under various Waterfall and Agile methodo logy projects. Involved in design of new business requirements, development, unit testing and deployment.



ananduk002@gmail.com

Kochi, India

in linkedin.com/in/anandukrishnannarayanan

П +917558874487

17 November, 1992

(O) @anandukrishnan narayanan

COMPANY PROFILE

Senior Software Developer **UST Global**

12/2015 - Present

Kochi, India

Worked on different projects with Anthem Enterprise [Digital & Commission] as a part of modernisation of mainframe projects to java spring RESTful services and NEW applications build with micro-services

Responsibilities

- Develop, test and deploy new applications
- Test, maintain and recommend application improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimisation
- Facilitate root cause analysis of system issues
- Multi-task and change from one task to another without loss of efficiency and composure
- Make good technical decisions that provide solutions to business challenges
- Clearly and regularly communicate with customers and colleagues

SKILLS

End to End Application Design & Development

Analytical & Problem solving

Analysis & Debugging

Agile Development Processes & Principles

Testing & Documentation

Ability to learn quickly

Customer Oriented

Communication & Interpersonal

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Client Appreciation from Anthem

* Client appreciation for delivering Log Analyser application in three months * For independently delivering a batch project using spring batch that can process(read & write) 1 billion data in 15 minutes within 2 sprints

Rewards and Recognition

Received R&R award 3 times while working with Anthem

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (09/2011 - 04/2015)

Toc H Institute of Science and Technology (CUSAT). Kochi, India

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Framework and Persistence

Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Spring Data Mongo, RESTful web services, Microservices, Junit

DRMS

Oracle, MS SQL Server, MongoDB

Web Technologies

Basics in HTML5, XML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular

Web Servers

Apache Tomcat, IBM Web Sphere

Operating System

Microsoft Windows, Mac OSX, Linux UBUNTU, Kali Linux

Tools and Utilities

IBM RSA, Clear Case, Eclipse, Rest Client, Maven, Bitbucket, Git, Jira

WORK EXPERIENCE

Log Analyser (01/2016 - 05/2016)

- Java, 1.7, Angular JS, Oracle 10g, Restful web services, HTML, CSS, node JS
- Reads the log files generated at a server location and updates an interactive UI with all the details from the log thereby severely reducing the time required by the developers to analyze the logs manually

Anthem- Shopper Individual Health Insurance Exchange (05/2016 - 11/2016)

- Java 1.7, spring 3.0, Spring Web Flow, JSP, SQL Database
- The application contains options for shopping & quoting of medical, dental and life insurance plans. User can create and modify applications for the selected plans

Anthem- Shopper Online Store Admin Console (Individual/Senior) (11/2016 - 02/2018)

- Spring 4.1.6, Java 1.7, Junit 4.12, MS SQL
- Admin console is an admin tool which is used for internal report generation purpose by Anthem employees. This was a modernization project which migrated the existing application from SOAP to RESTful & Spring boot and the front end was developed using Angular JS

Anthem- Commercial Sales Compensation (02/2018 - Present)

- Spring Boot 2.1.0, Java 1.8, Junit 4.12, Oracle, Mongo DB
- An application developed with micoservice architecture
- This project deals with the computation of the Agent commission based on the business criteria
- Worked on design, framework creation, development and deployment of 4 services and 2 batches developed with spring batch framework